# **WANGHAO TANG (Albert)**

Toronto, Canada, (226)-978-8228, wanghaotang18@gmail.com

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven and self-motivated recent Bachelor of Mathematics graduate from the University of Waterloo specializing in computer science and statistics with high level of experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with penchant for meeting deadlines. Excellent communicator with bilingual proficiency in English & Mandarin.

**EDUCATION** 

September 2016 - April 2020

September 2020 to April 2022

January 2021 - December 2021

Bachelor of Computer Science: University Of Waterloo Master of Project Management: Northeastern University CS50X Certificate
Harvard EDX

# **PROJECTS**

#### Project | Chess Project | Waterloo, Canada

- Leveraged advanced programming knowledge of C++ to develop an interactive chess game
- Used integrations including observer pattern, inheritance, and smart pointer to optimize UI interface overall experience
   Tested program and databases to identify issues and make necessary modifications
- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in Chess implementation
   Orchestrated efficient large-scale deployments via updates, including testing features and correcting code Identified plans and resources required to meet project goals and objectives by setting realistic timelines and checkpoints
- Drove team success through shared vision and recognition of quality performance
- Identified, reviewed, and applied policies and procedures by exercising informed judgment to achieve optimal performance

#### Project | Protector | Interactive Game | Waterloo, Canada

- Created a tower defense game called Protector using Android Studio
- Used debugging techniques to identify issues with computer code and resolve errors Used professional design tools to create characters, levels, layouts, and unique elements
- Established documents outlining concept, art, deliverable specifications, game flow charts and overall content to help keep projects moving working together cohesively
- · Followed specifications and technical limitations when designing to meet established design and gameplay objectives
- Introduction Video Link: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s3MugWt06qQ&t=69s">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s3MugWt06qQ&t=69s</a>

# Project | Mock Microsoft Homepage | Website | Xi'an, China

- Simulated Microsoft's official website home page using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Create a user login system using C#, ADO.NET
- Introduction Video Link: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l2-asWsbdAl&t=4s">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l2-asWsbdAl&t=4s</a>

# Project | weather forecast | Website | Toronto, Canada

- A webpage that can provide forecasted weather based on the entered city
- Users can leave comments and suggest improvements to the webpage
- Using React, Node.js, Express and MySQL
- Link: https://github.com/AlbertZxxcv/Forecasted

## WORKING EXPERIENCE

# Chinasoft International | Software Developer | September 2021 – December 2021

- Write unit test for Azure IoT (Internet of Things) Device Update (ADU) using C#
- · Participate in Microsoft outsourcing projects, cooperate with the Microsoft team, and participate in their weekly meeting.
- Assisted with the Microsoft team to improve the test coverage rate of the ADU source code.

# Xi'an Smart Innovation Information Technology | Software Developer | August 2018 - September 2018

- Assisted with the development of the firm's Java program
- Participated in the login system of Haier User Survey Program

#### Xi'an Xiamu Internet Technology | Software Developer | August 2017 – September 2017

- Acquired experience in understanding the preliminary flows of a large programming project
- Leveraged programming knowledge to develop small part of code in creating WeChat Mini Program for Chinese National Medical Products Administration information searching system

## **SKILLS**

Advanced programming proficiency in: C, C++, C#, Java, Android Studio, Python, R & R Markdown, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, React, Node.js, Express, Racket, Linux Command Line & MATLAB

Worked in both Agile and Waterfall working environment.

Understanding of: Gaussian Process, Kernal Method, SVM, Convolution and Recurrent Neural Network, Informed Search, Decision Trees & Variable Elimination Proven statistical knowledge of Applied Probability, Markov Process, Linear Regression Models, Generalized Linear Regression Models & Time Series